Martin Ertsås

martin@ertsas.io +47 92 21 79 82 martiert @ github Software Developer

SUMMARY

Technology

Developer of large, multithreaded systems for collaboration. Mainly working in C++ with embedded Linux systems. Coded multiple lower level components to support various architectural changes and making the code more modular.

Collaboration

Experienced in initiatives to share code across several time zones, and across different work cultures.

TECHNOLOGIES

- C++ Programming language (4.5)
- Git (4.0)
- Bash language (3.5)
- Python asyncio and aiohttp library (3.0)
- LATEX(2.5)

Processes

Passionate about contributor happiness. Both created and changed systems and pipelines to make developers face less obstacles while doing their job.

Learning

Continuously striving to learn and understand new technologies, and develop both hard and soft skills.

- Python programming language (4.0)
- Linux operating system (3.5)
- Linux userspace development (3.0)
- OpenEmbedded/Yocto Project (2.5)

EMPLOYMENT

Software Developer, Embedded Android development, Cisco, 2017 - present

Software Developer, Embedded C++ development, Cisco, 2012 - 2017

Software Developer, Windows and OS X development, Cisco, 2011 - 2012

Teaching assistant, Informatics teaching assistant, University of Oslo, 2008 - 2011

Exam grader, Grader in Numerical calculations, University of Oslo, 2010

EDUCATION

The University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway (2009 - 2011)

Master of Science program, Department of Informatics (specialties in physics simulations on GPUs)

The University of Oslo,, Oslo, Norway (2006 - 2009)

Master of Science program of Department of Mathematics (specialties in informatics)

SERVICE

Contributor, Kodeklubben.no Arduino assignments, (2015 - present)

Teacher, Lær Kidsa Koding, Oslo, (2015)